Víctor Ponce López



Contact

vponcelop<at>gmail.com victorponce.site Bristol, United Kingdom

Languages

Catalan ****(native), Spanish ★★★★ (native), English ****

(advanced reading/writing, fluent oral).

Français **** (intermediate reading/writing, basics oral).

Programming Languages, Libs, Tools, **Web and Environments**

Python, MATLAB, C++/C#/C, R, PyCharm, Netbeans, Eclipse, VS/VC++, SVN/GIT, Redmine, LATEX, XML, PostgreSQL, SQL, MySQL, Hive, Spark, Hadoop, CodaLab, Kaggle, Bash, PHP/HTML/CSS/JavaScript;

Deep Learning & Computer Vision libraries and toolboxes: ♥ Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras, GAN. CNN. LSTM. dlib. CUDA+CuDNN, Kinect™SDK, open{CV/NI/GL}, CNTK+; evolutionary computation and statistical pattern recognition: numpy, matplotlib, sklearn, optimtool, gatool, pmtk3,

OS Preferences

deap, pandas, statsmodel.

GNU/I inux ★★★★ Windows ★★★★ MacOS **** Android ★★★★ iOS ****

short bio

I am a Research Associate in the Dept. of Computer Science at the University of Bristol. I was a Research Scientist in Eurecat at the Big Data Analytics Unit. I hold a PhD at the the Dept. of Mathematics and Computer Science, University of Barcelona (UB). I received my B.Sc. degree in Computer Science and Engineering at the Faculty of Mathematics of UB, and my M.Sc. degree in Artificial Intelligence at the Polytechnic University of Catalonia (UPC). I was affiliated to the Computer Vision Center - Autonomous University of Barcelona (UAB)- and the Open University of Catalonia (UOC), in the groups HuPBA and SUNAI; and the group Qarma at the Laboratoire d'Informatique Fondamentalle (LIF), Aix-Marseille Université.

experience

2017-Present **University of Bristol**

Bristol, United Kingdom

Postdoctoral Research Associate, Dept. of Computer Science.

- Time-Series Predictive Analysis of Seasonal Ground Surface Deformation.
- Computer Vision for Human Activity Recognition in Home Healthcare.
- Domain Adaptation, Self-Supervised Learning, GANs, Person Re-IDentification.

Eurecat Technology Center of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, Open University of 2010-2017 Catalonia, Computer Vision Center, and Dept. of Justice, Government of Catalonia

> Research Scientist, PostDoc, Collaboration in Research projects, international PhD stay, 40+ scientific publications and peer-reviews, teaching and material preparation, organization/attendance on international conferences, events, and seminars.

- 4 impact factor journals, 17 conference proceedings, and 1 book chapter.
- ChaLearn Looking At People collaboration with Microsoft, NVIDIA, Google, Amazon, Disney, Facebook, Orange, MWC-GSMA.
- · Research projects on human behavior analysis within real-world domains.

Past-2010 Barcelona's Council: Dept. of Education, Culture and Welfare

Barcelona, Spain

Software Engineer, IT Services.

education

2012-2016 Ph.D. in Mathematics and Computer Science

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona

Dissertation: "Evolutionary Bags of Space-Time Features for Human Analysis." Cum

Laude (spanish) and International Mention.

2010-2012 M.Sc in Artificial Intelligence

Polytechnic University of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, and Rovira i Virgili University.

Dissertation: "Multi-Modal Human Gesture Recognition combining Dynamic Program-

ming and Probabilistic Methods." With Honors.

2006-2010 **B.Sc in Computer Science: Systems engineering**

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona.

Dissertation: "Analysis of Oral and Gestural Expression using an Artificial Vision Sys-

tem." With Honors.

extracurricular

2006-Present **Driving license**

2004-Present **Martial Arts licenses** Hapkido 2nd Black Belt

1998-2004 Musical language and Piano licenses

interests

I'm a research & technology passionate. My main interests are computer vision, machine learning, and evolutionary computation for real-world applications. I like to be up to date with latest research and cutting-edge technology to foresee next future trends and needs.

PARTICIPATION IN RESEARCH PROJECTS AND TECHNOLOGICAL TRANSFER:

Project Title: Digital Environment for the Analysis and Detection of Ground Surface Deformation.

Funding Entity: UK Research and Innovation (UKRI).

Participant Entities: University of Bristol, SatSense, Terrafirma, TRE-Altamira.

Duration: 2019/05/20 to 2019/12/23. **Project Responsible**: Juliet Biggs. **Number of Researchers involved**: >10

Project Title: SPHERE, a Sensor Platform for HEalthcare in a Residential Environment.

Funding Entity: EPSRC (Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council), University of

Bristol.

Participant Entities: IBM, Toshiba, Bristol City Council, Universities of Southampton, Cambridge

and Reading, KWMC.

Duration: 2017/01/31 to 2022/01/31.

Project Responsible: Ian Craddock, Majid Mirmehdi, Dima Damen.

Number of Researchers involved: >50

Project Title: eTur 2020.

Funding Entity: Centro para el Desarrollo Tecnológico Industrial (CDTI), MINECO, Spanish

Government.

Participant Entities: Tecnocom, Groupalia, Eurecat, Eurona, Solusoft, Compartia, Zemsania.

Duration: from 2017/05/05 to 2017/09/31.

Project Responsible: Jesus Carlos Villagra Laso, Jose Mena Roldan, Marc Torrent, Víctor Ponce

López.

Number of Researchers involved: >10

Project Title: Tourism Management.

Funding Entity: Barcelona Council, GSM, and Mobile World Capital.

Participant Entities: Barcelona Council, Orange, GSM, MWC, Eurecat, DFRC, D-Lab.

Duration: from 2017/02/15 to 2018/04/31.

Project Responsible: Marc Torrent Moreno, Bárbara Vallespín Peré.

Number of Researchers involved: >10

Project Title: New Technologies for Virtual and Augmented Reality (VR360).

Funding Entity: Eurecat, Government of Catalonia.

Participant Entities: Eurecat Tecnology Center of Catalonia, Computer Vision Center.

Duration: from 2017/04/01 to 2018/12/31. **Project Responsible**: Rafael Redondo. **Number of Researchers involved**: >10

Project Title: Social Car.

Funding Entity: European Union Horizon 2020 No 636427.

Participant Entities: CERTH. MOVENDA. TAXISTOP. SUPSI. UWH. ZIGHT. ABACUS.

STRATEGIC STUFF, UNIABDN, IBI Group, FIT, VECTOS, BERMAG, TTS Italia, Eurecat.

Duration: from 2015/09/01 to 2017/11/31.

Project Responsible: Dionisis Kehagias, Andrea Emilio Rizzoli

Number of Researchers involved: >10

Project Title: ChaLearn Looking at People: Apparent Personality Analysis on First Impressions.

Funding Entity: ChaLearn.

Participant Entities: Microsoft Research, NVIDIA, Amazon, Google, Disney Research, Aix-Marseille Université, *Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona* (UAB), *Universitat de Barcelona* (UB),

Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (UOC). **Duration**: from 2014/09/22 to 2016/11/31.

Project Responsible: Isabelle Guyon, Sergio Escalera.

Number of Researchers involved: >20

Project Title: ChaLearn Looking at People: Gesture Challenge.

Funding Entity: European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2014, ChaLearn.

Participant Entities: Microsoft Research, Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona (UAB), Universitat

de Barcelona (UB), Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (UOC).

Duration: from 2013/12/09 to 2014/10/12

Project Responsible: Isabelle Guyon, Sergio Escalera.

Number of Researchers involved: >20

Project Title: Spatio-Temporal Sub-Gesture Definition for Automatic Human Behaviour Analysis.

Funding Entity: FI-DGR 2013. AGAUR, Generalitat of Catalonia.

Participant Entities: Open University of Barcelona (UOC).

Duration: from 2013/02/01 until 2016/01/31 **Project Responsible**: Xavier Baró Solé. **Number of Researchers involved**: 5

Project Title: ReMedi: Multi-modal Home Assistive Technology for Dementia and Alzheimer's

Diseases.

Funding Entity: Obra Social La Caixa.

Participant Entities: Bosch and Gimpera Foundation (FBG), University of Barcelona.

Duration: from 2012/04/01 until 2013/01/31 **Project Responsible**: Oriol Pujol Vila. **Number of Researchers involved**: 7

Project Title: Human Behaviour Analysis in Victim-Offender Mediations. **Funding Entity**: Department of Justice of the *Generalitat* of Catalonia.

Duration: from 2012/02/01 until 2013/03/31

Project Responsibles: Víctor Ponce López, Sergio Escalera Guerrero, Xavier Baró Solé.

Number of Researchers involved: 5

Project Title: Analysis of Oral and Gestural Expression using an Artificial Vision System.

Funding Entity: University of Barcelona. **Duration**: from: 2010/06/01 until 2010/11/01

Project Responsible: Sergio Escalera, Xavier Baró, Miguel A. Bautista, Víctor Ponce, Verónica

Violant.

Number of Researchers involved: 8

SCHOLARSHIPS AND GRANTS:

- 2019: **UKRI Grant** from UK Research and Innovation for Research Projects in Digital Environment.
- 2017: **EPSRC and IRC Grants,** UK Engineering and Physical Sciences and International Research Councils, Grant *EP/K031910/1*.
- 2016: **Research support** provided by Microsoft Research, Microsoft CodaLab, the Laboratoire de Recherche en Informatique of Paris Sud University, INRIA-Saclay and the Paris-Saclay Center for Data Science (CDS).
- 2015: **European Comission Horizon 2020 (H2020)** granted project SEE.4C under call *H2020-ICT 2015*.
 - **Grant** to support research projects of consolidated groups by the Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness, **Spanish Government**. *TIN2015-66951-C2-2-R*.
- 2014: Labex ARCHIMEDE Grant for a Research Project. Marseille INstitute of MAthematics and Computer Science (MIN-MACS). Laboratoire d'Informatique Fondamentalle, Aix-Marseille Université, UMR CNRS 7279.
- 2013: **FI-DGR 2013 Grant** for **Formation in Research** from the 'Agència de Gestió d'Ajuts Universitaris i de Recerca' (AGAUR), **Generalitat, Catalan Government.** 2013FI-B01037.
 - **Grant** to support Spanish research projects of consolidated groups by the Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness, **Spanish Government**. *TIN2013-43478-P*.
- 2012: **PMID Grant** for **Teaching Innovation Projects** from **University of Barcelona**. Code: 2012PID-UB/152.

Grant to support research projects of consolidated groups by the Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness, **Spanish Government**. *TIN2012-38187-C03-02*.

CEJFE Grant for a research project with the **Department of Justice** (*Generalitat* of Catalonia). Center of Legal Studies and Specialized Formation. Resolution id: JUS/237/2011.

Grant from *Obra Social La Caixa* for a **Research Project** at the Department of Applied Mathematics and Analysis of the **University of Barcelona**. Grant id: 5800201204001.

- 2011: **Scholarship** for *Web administration* of the **Faculty of Mathematics** of the University of Barcelona. Code: 1-11PUI.
 - **Grant** to support research projects from IMSERSO, Ministry of Sanity, **Spanish Government**. *MEDIMINDER*.
 - Grant to support research and technological projects from RecerCaixa. REMEDI.
- 2010: Collaboration Scholarship for Teaching Innovation Projects with the Department of Applied Mathematics and Analysis of the University of Barcelona. Code: 2-10ESC.
- 2009: **PMID Grant** for **Teaching Innovation Projects** from **University of Barcelona**. Code: 2009PID-UB/04.

OTHER PUBLIC AND PRIVATE PROJECTS INVOLVED:

- 2017-

Present: **Post-Doctoral Research Associate** at the University of Bristol.

- 2016: Research Scientist at Eurecat, Technology Centre of Catalonia.
- 2016: **Post-Doc Researcher** at the **Computer Vision Center**, *Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona*.
- 2010: **Software Engineer and IT Services** at the Education Management, Culture and Welfare of the **Barcelona Council**.

• PEER REVIEWING (Verified by https://publons.com/a/1202458) (Year) (#Reviews)

- o IEEE Transactions on Evolutionary Computation 2019(1).
- o British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2019(4).
- IEEE Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, Explanatory Computer Vision Workshop ECVW @ CVPR, 2017(1).

- IEEE Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, Deep Vision Workshop DV2017 @ CVPR. 2017(1).
- IEEE Transactions on Affective Computing, 2017(2).
- IET Computer Vision 2016(1) 2017(3).
- On Editorial Board Membership for IEEE Transactions on Affective Computing, 2016.
- IEEE International Conference on Automatic Face and Gesture Recognition (FG), 2016(2)-2017(2)-2018(4)-2019(1).
- IEEE European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) Workshops, 2014(2) 2016 (2).
- IEEE Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Conference Workshops, 2016 (3).
- IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) Workshops, 2015 (committee member).
- IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), 2015 (5).
- IEEE Transactions on Multimedia, 2014(1).
- Journal of Machine Learning Research (JMLR), 2013(1) 2014(2).

ORGANIZATION AND SCIENTIFIC PROGRAM COMMITTEE (PC) MEMBER:

- o Mentor at the ImaginChallenge 2016. Obra Social La Caixa.
- ECCV 2016 Workshop ChaLearn Looking at People: First Impressions.
- CVCR&D 2016 Workshop: Computer Vision Center, Research and Development advances.
- o ECCV 2014 Workshop ChaLearn Looking at People: Gesture Recognition.
- o CCIA 2014 Member of the organization.
- o ICCV 2011 Member of the organization.

PARTICIPATION IN CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS:

- Digital Environment Stakeholder Workshop Meeting, 2019, Engineering House, Bristol
- International Conference on Image Analysis and Processing (ICIAP), 2019.
- o European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) Person-In-Context Workshop, 2018.
- British Machine Vision Association (BMVA) Symposium, Technical meeting in Computer Vision for Smart Environments and Assisted Living.
- Bristol Vision Institute Research Colloquium, 2018. Participant and assistant.
- >10 seminars from the Bristol Vision Institute, Visual Information Lab, and SPHERE, at the University of Bristol. Participation and assistant.
- Mobile World Congress, Exhibitor Staff at the Big Data Innovation City, 2017, Barcelona.
- o European Workshop on Reinforcement Learning (EWRL), 2016, Barcelona. Assistant.
- o Intel Code Modernization Workshop 2016, Barcelona. Assistant.
- Big Data Congress and Eurecat Mobile Forum 2016, Barcelona. Participant and assistant.
- Assistance in *more than 20 seminars* covering different areas in the **Artificial Intelligence** and **Computer Vision** at the Computer Vision Center of the UAB in the range of years between 2010-2016.
- Deep learning Seminar meetups at Polytechnic University of Catalonia (UPC) and Pompeu Fabra University (UPF), 2016.
- o British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC) 2015. Conference assistant and participant.
- Seminars and workshops held by QARMA group at Centre de Mathématiques et Informatique (CMI). Laboratoire d'Informatique Fondamentale, Aix-Université de Marseille, 2014.
- o European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2014. Conference assistant and participant. Workshop ChaLearn Looking At People challenge organizer.
- o Congrés Internacional de l'Associació Catalana d'Intel·ligència Artificial (CCIA) 2014. Facultad de Matemáticas, Universitat de Barcelona. Member of the Committee.
- o *International Conference on Multimodal Interaction (ICMI)* 2013. Coogee Bay Hotel, Sydney, Australia. Conference assistant and participant.
- o ENS/INRIA Computer Vision and Machine Learning Summer School 2013. Participant.
- o Mobile World Congress (MWC) 2013. Exhibitor Attendee.
- International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR) 2012. Tsukuba Science City, Japan. Conference assistant and participant.

- o Mobile World Congress (MWC) 2012. Congress assistant.
- o International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2011. Member of the Organization Committee and conference assistant.
- o International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) 2011. Conference assistant participant at the Doctoral Consortium.

• TEACHING:

- o Co-supervision of B.Sc and M.Sc Students. Thesis at University of Bristol, 2017-2018.
- Support and preparation of teaching material for the Computer Vision course in the Computer Science degree at the Faculty of Mathematics. University of Barcelona, 2014.
- o Co-supervision of Student's B.Sc. Thesis at University of Barcelona, 2013.
- Grant for Teaching Innovation Projects with code 2012PID-UB/152 from the University of Barcelona.
- Artificial Intelligence Xerrades Taller (Working Talks) at the Faculty of Mathematics (University of Barcelona). Practical Works, Title: "Artificial Intelligence: How do the machines see?" January 2011. Organizer: Dr. Sergio Escalera.
- o ITACA UAB. Days for presenting the Complex Problems and activities in the 'Campus Ítaca' at the Autonomous University of Barcelona. 2010-2015.

HONORS, AWARDS AND OTHER MERITS:

- Author of 4 impact factor journals and 17 conference proceedings.
- >40 verified peer-reviews in impact factor journals and international conference proceedings.
- o Runner up for the CERCA Pioneer awards 2016.
- o Runner up at the Big Data Talent Awards, Barcelona Big Data Congress 2016.
- o International Mention and Cum Laude distinction for the Ph.D. Thesis.
- Obtention of Honors both for B.Sc. and M.Sc. Theses.
- o Award for the best Spanish Bachelor Project by the *AENUI*, with the work for automatically determine the success of a communication.